var data = [
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue regarding the transmembrane proteins?",
        options: ["The membrane proteins are also of tremendous biomedical importance","They are not drug targets or receptors","They are responsible for performing a wide variety of important functions in a cell, such as signal transduction, cross-membrane transport, and energy conversion","Constitute up to 30% of all cellular proteins"],
        correct_option: "They are not drug targets or receptors"
    },
    {
        question: "r-RNA originates from-",
        options: ["Nucleus","Nucleolous","Cytoplasm","ER"],
        correct_option: "Nucleolous"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the following which is longest cell-",
        options: ["Hemp","Ramie","Jute","Nerve fibre"],
        correct_option: "Nerve fibre"
    },
    {
        question: "The structural level of a protein least affected by a disruption in hydrogen bond is the",
        options: ["secondary level","tertiary level","primary level","quaternary level"],
        correct_option: "primary level"
    },
    {
        question: "The probability of a son to be color blind for parent with color blind father and normal homozygous mother would be",
        options: ["0%","25%","50%","100%"],
        correct_option: "0%"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue about comparative genomics?",
        options: ["It is comparison of whole genomes from different organisms","It includes comparison of gene number, gene location, and gene content from these genomes","It provides insights into the mechanism of genome evolution and gene transfer among genomes","It doesn’t help to reveal the extent of conservation among genomes"],
        correct_option: "It provides insights into the mechanism of genome evolution and gene transfer among genomes"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue about Whole Genome Alignment?",
        options: ["This helps to reveal the presence of conserved functional elements","It doesn’t help to understand sequence conservation between genomes","It be accomplished through direct genome comparison or genome alignment","The alignment at the genome level is fundamentally no different from the basic sequence \n alignment"],
        correct_option: "It doesn’t help to understand sequence conservation between genomes"
    },
    {
        question: "Coregenes is a web-based program that determines a ________ set of genes based on comparison of \n ________ small genomes.",
        options: ["vast, four","core, fifteen","core, four","vast, fifteen"],
        correct_option: "core, four"
    },
    {
        question: "The shotgun approach _______ sequences clones from _____ of cloned DNA.",
        options: ["randomly, one end","randomly, both ends","specifically, both ends","specifically, one end"],
        correct_option: "randomly, both ends"
    },
    {
        question: "The hierarchical genome sequencing approach is ______",
        options: ["entirely dissimilar to the shotgun approach","dissimilar to the shotgun approach","similar to the shotgun approach, but on a larger scale","similar to the shotgun approach, but on a smaller scale"],
        correct_option: "similar to the shotgun approach, but on a smaller scale"
    },
    {
        question: "The first genomic libraries were cloned in ___________",
        options: ["Plasmid","Bacteria","Human","Plants"],
        correct_option: "Plasmid"
    },
    {
        question: "Genomic library construction is concerned with ________",
        options: ["Gene isolation","Protein production","Antibiotics","Regeneration"],
        correct_option: "Gene isolation"
    },
    {
        question: "Which DNA is restricted to making a genomic library?",
        options: ["Genomic","Plasmid","Phage","Plant"],
        correct_option: "Genomic"
    },
    {
        question: "A genomic library is a collection of _____________",
        options: ["Genes","Proteins","Vectors","Recombinants"],
        correct_option: "Recombinants"
    },
    {
        question: "The Clarke and Carbon formula relates the ____________ of including a DNA fragment in a random \n library",
        options: ["Probability","Effects","Temperature change","Vector requirement"],
        correct_option: "Probability"
    },
    {
        question: "Which kind of packing is done for the fragmented genes?",
        options: ["In vivo","Population","Group","In vitro"],
        correct_option: "In vitro"
    },
    {
        question: "The ‘Charon series’ belongs to series of __________",
        options: ["Genes","Vectors","Hosts","Enzymes"],
        correct_option: "Vectors"
    },
    {
        question: "Lambda EMBL3 is a __________",
        options: ["Gene","Phage","Phage Vector","Protein"],
        correct_option: "Phage Vector"
    },
    {
        question: "How many types of mapping there?",
        options: ["1","2","3","4"],
        correct_option: "2"
    },
    {
        question: "The distance between two genes is measured in units known as ________",
        options: ["nanomorgan","micromorgan","millimorgan","centimorgan"],
        correct_option: "centimorgan"
    },
    {
        question: "Genetic markers are ______ portions of a _______ whose inheritance patterns can be followed",
        options: ["unidentifiable, genes","unidentifiable, chromosome","identifiable, chromosome","identifiable, genes"],
        correct_option: "identifiable, chromosome"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is incorrect regarding gene ontology?",
        options: ["There is standardization of the names and activities","There is no standardization of associated pathways","It provides consistency in describing overall protein functions","It facilitates grouping of proteins of related functions"],
        correct_option: "There is no standardization of associated pathways"
    },
    {
        question: "Macrorestriction is a type of physical mapping wherein the high molecular weight DNA is digested \n with a restriction enzyme having a low number of restriction sites.",
        options: ["True","False","Maybe true or false","both true and false"],
        correct_option: "True"
    },
    {
        question: "Chain termination is a type of _______",
        options: ["Sequencing","Vector generation","Antibiotic production","Gene manipulation"],
        correct_option: "Sequencing"
    },
    {
        question: "The first significant DNA sequence to be obtained was that of",
        options: ["Lambda","Plasmid","Lactose","Mammals"],
        correct_option: "Lambda"
    },
    {
        question: "Which type of DNA cleavage is done in the Maxam Gilbert method?",
        options: ["Edge","Interstitial","Base-specific","Gene-specific"],
        correct_option: "Base-specific"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the main enzyme component of Sanger sequencing",
        options: ["Helicase","Polymerase","Nuclease","Gyrase"],
        correct_option: "Polymerase"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is used by DNA polymerase as a substrate?",
        options: ["Sucrose","Lactose","Nucleotide","Nucleoside"],
        correct_option: "Nucleotide"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following acts as a chain terminator?",
        options: ["Exogenous","DNA","Deoxynucleotides","Dideoxynucleotides"],
        correct_option: "Dideoxynucleotides"
    },
    {
        question: "The Klenow fragment is basically a ________",
        options: ["DNA hybrid","DNA polymerase","RNA polymerase","Promoter"],
        correct_option: "DNA polymerase"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is untrue about base calling and assembly programs?",
        options: ["The first step toward genome assembly includes derive base calls","The first step toward genome assembly includes assigning associated quality scores","One of the steps is to assemble the sequence reads into contiguous sequences","There is no identifying overlap between sequence fragments"],
        correct_option: "There is no identifying overlap between sequence fragments"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is incorrect about Phred?",
        options: ["It is a UNIX program","It doesn’t give a probability score in output","It is used for base calling","It uses a Fourier analysis to resolve fluorescence traces and predict actual peak locations of bases"],
        correct_option: "It doesn’t give a probability score in output"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is the most important aspect of planning and designing \n a good sequencing experiment?",
        options: ["Careful choice of sample(s) and control(s)","Effective data analysis","Robust and precise experimental methods","All of the above"],
        correct_option: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "You need to use a first generation sequencing method for de novo sequencing, which \n template should give optimum results for this project?",
        options: ["Genomic DNA","PCR product","Bacterial artificial chromosome","Plasmid DNA"],
        correct_option: "Bacterial artificial chromosome"
    },
    {
        question: "What will heterozygous single nucleotide substitution look like on your chromatogram?",
        options: ["Two peaks of equal height at the same position","One peak twice the height of those around it","Two peaks in the same position, one twice the height of the other","Three peaks of equal height at the same position"],
        correct_option: "Two peaks of equal height at the same position"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following main component of mass spectroscopy deal with resolving the ions into \n their characteristics mass components according to their mass-to-charge ratio?",
        options: ["Ion source","Analyzer","Detector System","Analyzer tube"],
        correct_option: "Analyzer"
    },
    {
        question: "Who discovered the mass spectrometer?",
        options: ["Francis Aston","J. J Thomson","Ernest O. Lawrence","Walter Kaufmann"],
        correct_option: "J. J Thomson"
    },
    {
        question: "In which state of matter mass spectroscopy is being performed?",
        options: ["solid","liquid","gaseous","plasma"],
        correct_option: "gaseous"
    },
    {
        question: "Which species of the following is used to bombard with the sample for which mass spectroscopy \n has been performed? ",
        options: ["Alpha particles","Neutrons","Electrons","Protons"],
        correct_option: "Electrons"
    },
    {
        question: "Separation of ions in mass spectrometer take place on the basis of which of the following?",
        options: ["Mass","Charge","Molecular weight","Mass to charge ratio"],
        correct_option: "Mass to charge ratio"
    },
    {
        question: "Which type of ionic species are allowed to pass through the slit and reach the collecting plate?",
        options: ["Negative ions of all masses","positive ions of the specific mass","Negative ions of the specific mass","Positive ions of all masses"],
        correct_option: "positive ions of the specific mass"
    },
    {
        question: "Linkage ________ as the distance between two genes ___________",
        options: ["Decreases, decreases","Unaffected, Decreases","Decreases, Increases","Increases, Increases"],
        correct_option: "Decreases, Increases"
    },
    {
        question: "If you suddenly observe linkage between two genes that are present in two chromosomes, this can \n be due to _______________",
        options: ["Coupling","Translocation","Inversion","Non-homologous end joining"],
        correct_option: "Translocation"
    },
    {
        question: "Accurate mapping of genes can be done using _____",
        options: ["Two point mapping","Three point mapping","Single gene mapping","None of the mentioned"],
        correct_option: "Three point mapping"
    },
    {
        question: "Recombination occurs in ________",
        options: ["Single strand stage","Two strand stage","Three strand stage","Four stand stage"],
        correct_option: "Four stand stage"
    },
    {
        question: "Many levels of clone redundancy may be required to build a consensus map because individual \n clones can have ______",
        options: ["rearrangements","deletions","two separate fragments","vectors"],
        correct_option: "vectors"
    },
    {
        question: "A tripeptide has _________",
        options: ["3 amino acids and 1 peptide bond","3 amino acids and 2 peptide bonds","3 amino acids and 3 peptide bonds","3 amino acids and 4 peptide bonds"],
        correct_option: "3 amino acids and 2 peptide bonds"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a 39-residue hormone of the anterior pituitary gland?",
        options: ["Corticotropin","Glucagon","Insulin","Bradykinin"],
        correct_option: "Corticotropin"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is not the classified form of conjugated proteins?",
        options: ["Lipoproteins","Glycoproteins","Metalloproteins","Complete proteins"],
        correct_option: "Complete proteins"
    },
    {
        question: "Unfolding of a protein can be termed as _________",
        options: ["Renaturation","Denaturation","Oxidation","Reduction"],
        correct_option: "Denaturation"
    },  
]

export default data;